Peter Fallon - Gallery Press collection, circa 1967-1998
Emory University
Peter Fallon - Gallery Press collection, circa 1967-1998
Fallon, Peter.
Manuscript Collection No. 817
124.5 linear ft. (224 boxes) and 127 oversized papers (OP)
Personal and literary papers of Irish poet and publisher Peter Fallon, as well as the archives of the Gallery Press.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Purchase, 1998.
Restrictions on access
Special restrictions apply: Collection stored off-site. Researchers must contact MARBL in advance to access this collection.
Subseries 2.2. and Series 8: Letters by Seamus Heaney are closed to researchers.
Biographical or Historical Note
Peter Fallon, poet, editor and publisher, was born in Germany in 1951 but spent his early years on a farm in County Meath, Ireland. He graduated in 1975 with a B.A. in English Language and Literature and an H.Dip. Ed from Trinity College. In 1970, at the age of eighteen, he founded The Gallery Press that has published poems and plays by the Ireland’s finest established and emerging authors. The Gallery Press is recognised as the pre-eminent literary publishing house in Ireland. Among the writers it publishes are John Banville, Ciaran Carson, Medbh McGuckian, Derek Mahon, John Montague, Nuala Ní Dhomhnaill, and the playwright Brian Friel. The press has also published books by Paul Durcan, Seamus Heaney, and Paul Muldoon.
Fallon first began touring the United States, Europe, and Japan in 1972 and has since given readings, lectures and workshops at over one hundred colleges and universities. In 1976-1977 he served as poet-in-residence at Deerfield Academy in Massachusetts and in 1979 Fallon was the International Poet-in-Residence in the Indiana Public Schools. Fallon acted as fiction editor at the O'Brien press from 1980-1985. The National Arts Council of Ireland awarded Fallon an Arts Council bursary in 1981. In 1990 he and Derek Mahon edited The Penguin Book of Contemporary Irish Poetry. Peter Fallon's own collections of poems include The Speaking Stones, Winter Work, The News and Weather, Eye to Eye, and News Of the World: Selected and New Poems. A selection of his poems, News of the World: Selected Poems, was published in the United States by Wake Forest University Press.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains the records of The Gallery Press and Peter Fallon from ca. 1967-1998. The records include literary manuscripts, correspondence files, subject files, printed material, and photographs.
Arrangement Note
Organized into eight series: (1) Literary manuscripts, (2) Correspondence, (3) Peter Fallon, (4) Subject files, (5) Printed material, (6) Photographs, (7) Ephemera, and (8) Unprocessed additions.
Selected Search Terms
Corporate Names
After Hours Books.; Deerfield Press.; Gallery Press (Loughcrew, Ireland); O'Brien Press.; Tara Telephone.
Topical Terms
American poetry--20th century.; English drama--Irish authors--20th century.; English literature--Irish authors--20th century.; English poetry--Irish authors--20th century.; Irish poetry--20th century.; Poets, American--20th century.; Poets, Irish--20th century.; Publishers and publishing--Ireland.
Geographic Names
Ireland--Drama--20th century.
Form/Genre Terms
Manuscripts.; Poems.; Plays.
Related Materials in This Repository
Ciaran Carson papers, Ted Hughes papers, Michael Longley papers, Medbh McGuckian papers, Derek Mahon papers, Paul Muldoon papers, Desmond O'Grady papers, Frank Ormsby papers, and James Simmons papers.
Description of Series
- Literary manuscripts, 1969-1998, Series 1; Boxes 1-111
  Scope and Content Note
  The series contains files relating to authors who have published works through the Gallery Press (1969-1988), Gallery Press in conjunction with Deerfield Press, O'Brien Press (1980-1980), and Oldcastle Enterprises/After Hours Books. The files may include biographical information on the author, correspondence, manuscripts and typescripts of their works, and page proofs and mock-ups. Additional correspondence may be found in Literary Correspondence (Subseries 2.2) and press and publicity materials may be found in Publicity files on authors (Subseries 5.1).
  Arrangement Note
  Organized into five subseries: (1.1) Gallery Press author files, (1.2) Gallery Press submission files, (1.3) Deerfield Press author files, (1.4) O'Brien Press author files, and (1.5) Oldcastle Enterprises/After Hours Books author files.
  - Gallery Press author files, 1969-1998, Subseries 1.1; Boxes 1-85
    - Archer, Nuala, Biographical (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Archer, Nuala, Correspondence, 1980-1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Archer, Nuala, Other published works (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Archer, Nuala, Poems (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Archer, Nuala, Poems (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Archer, Nuala, "Attic Antics" (unpublished collection), MS (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Archer, Nuala, "Attic Antics" (unpublished collection), MS (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Archer, Nuala, "Attic Antics" (unpublished collection), MS (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Archer, Nuala, From A Mobile Home, MS poems (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Archer, Nuala, "Between Swilly and Sewanee," Archer selection from Two Women, Two Shores (Salmon, 1989), MS (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Archer, Nuala, Whale on a Line, MS (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Archer, Nuala, Whale on the Line, MS (1 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Archer, Nuala, Whale on the Line, MS (2 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Archer, Nuala, Whale on the Line, MS (3 of 3) (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Banville, John, Biographical (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Banville, John, Correspondence, 1977-1993 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Banville, John, Correspondence, 1993-1996 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Banville, John, Correspondence, 1996-1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Banville, John, Other published works (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Artwork (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Mock-ups with corrections (photocopy) (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Photocopy of book with corrections (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Proof with corrections (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Proof with corrections (Box OP1)
    - Banville, John, The Ark, Proof (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Banville, John, The Broken Jug, Book jacket material (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Banville, John, The Broken Jug, TS with corrections (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Banville, John, The Broken Jug, TS with corrections (2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Banville, John, The Broken Jug, Miscellaneous (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Banville, John, The Broken Jug, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Banville, John, The Broken Jug, Proof with corrections (photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Banville, John, Ghosts, Book jacket material (photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Banville, John, Kepler: A Novel (Secker and Warburg, 1981), TS with corrections (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Book jacket material (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Photocopy of book with corrections (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Photocopy with corrections (incomplete) (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Proof with corrections (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Proof with corrections (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Proof with corrections (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Banville, John, Long Lankin, Proof with corrections (incomplete) (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Banville, John, Nightspawn, Book jacket material (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Banville, John, Nightspawn, Mock-ups with corrections (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Banville, John, Nightspawn, Mock-ups with corrections (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Banville, John, Nightspawn, Proof with corrections (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Banville, John, Nightspawn, Proof (photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Banville, John, "Rondo," [variant title of Seascape (1994 teleplay)] TS (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Behan, Brendan, Correspondence, 1980-1990 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Behan, Brendan, Murphy, Maeve, Untitled Dissertation [1982], TS (photocopy); Ó Siochrús, Padraig, An Giall [English translation], MS (photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Behan, Brendan, Other published works (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Behan, Brendan, An Giall, Bound TS [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Book jacket material (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Book jacket material (Box OP2)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Critical essays by Declan Kiberd, TS with corrections (photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, TS with corrections (photocopy) [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, TS with corrections (photocopy) [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, TS with corrections (incomplete photocopy) [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Poems, TS with notations (photocopy) [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, TS with corrections [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 13)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Poems, TS with corrections [in Irish] (Box 4, Folder 14)
    - Behan, Brendan, Poems and a Play in Irish, Galley proofs with corrections [in Irish] (Box OP3)
    - Bourke, Ken, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    - Bourke, Ken, Wild Harvest, TS with corrections (Box 4, Folder 16)
    - Boland, Eavan [See: Hayes, Maurice (ed.), Flight Path] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Butler, Hubert [See: Hayes, Maurice (ed.), Flight Path] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Cannon, Moya, Correspondence, 1986-1997 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    - Cannon, Moya, Poems (Box 4, Folder 18)
    - Cannon, Moya, "Listening Clay," [variant title of Oar] TS with corrections (Box 4, Folder 19)
    - Cannon, Moya, Oar, TS with corrections (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Cannon, Moya, "Orpheus in Connaught," [variant title of The Parchment Boat] Miscellaneous (Box 4, Folder 21)
    - Cannon, Moya, "Orpheus in Connaught," [variant title of The Parchment Boat] TS with corrections (Box 4, Folder 22)
    - Cannon, Moya, The Parchment Boat, Mock-ups with author's corrections (photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 23)
    - Cannon, Moya, The Parchment Boat, Mock-ups with corrections (photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Cannon, Moya, The Parchment Boat, Mock-ups with corrections (photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Cannon, Moya, The Parchment Boat, Mock-ups with corrections (photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Cannon, Moya, The Parchment Boat, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Cannon, Moya, The Parchment Boat, TS with holographic corrections (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Carr, Marina, Biographical (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Carr, Marina, Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Carr, Marina, Photographs (photocopies) (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, Book jacket material (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, Miscellaneous (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, Mock-ups with corrections (photocopy) (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, TS with corrections (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, TS with corrections (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Carr, Marina, The Mai, TS (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Correspondence, 1977-1988 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Correspondence, 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Correspondence, 1991-1996 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Correspondence, undated (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Miscellaneous [with 1931 Ordnance Survey Map, Introduction] (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Other published works (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti, Miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti, Proofs with corrections (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti, TS with corrections (photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Belfast Confetti, TS poems (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Carson, Ciaran, First Language, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Carson, Ciaran, First Language, Proofs with corrections (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Carson, Ciarna, First Language, Proofs (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Carson, Ciaran, First Language, TS poems (includes 1992-1993 correspondence) (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Carson, Ciaran, First Language, TS with corrections (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Carson, Ciaran, In and Out of Time, TS with corrections (photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, Original cover art by Michael Kane (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, Mock-ups (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, Proofs with corrections (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, Proofs with corrections (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, Proofs with corrections (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, Proofs with corrections (Box OP4)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, TS with corrections (photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, TS with corrections (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The Irish for No, TS poems (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Letters from the Alphabet, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Letters from the Alphabet, TS with corrections (photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Letters from the Alphabet, TS with corrections (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The New Estate and Other Poems, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The New Estate and Other Poems, Proofs with corrections (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The New Estate and Other Poems, Proofs with corrections (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - Carson, Ciaran, The New Estate and Other Poems, TS with corrections (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Opera Et Cetera, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Opera Et Cetera, Proofs with corrections (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Opera Et Cetera, Proofs with corrections (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Opera Et Cetera, Proofs (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Opera Et Cetera, TS poems with corrections (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Carson, Ciaran, Opera Et Cetera, TS with corrections (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Clarke, Austin [See: Hayes, Maurice (ed.), Flight Path] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Clarkin, Sean, Book jacket material (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Clarkin, Sean, Correspondence, 1973-1988 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Clarkin, Sean, Without Frenzy, TS with corrections (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Clarkin, Sean, Without Frenzy, TS (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Clifton, Harry, Artwork (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Clifton, Harry, Correspondence, 1977-1989 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Clifton, Harry, Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Clifton, Harry, Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Clifton, Harry, Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Clifton, Harry, Other published works (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Clifton, Harry, TS poems (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Clifton, Harry, Comparative Lives, Galley proofs with corrections (Box OP5)
    - Clifton, Harry, Comparative Lives, TS poems (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Clifton, Harry, Comparative Lives, TS with corrections (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, Miscellaneous (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, Mock-ups (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, Proofs with corrections (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, Proofs with corrections (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, TS poems (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Desert Route, TS poems (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Liberal Cage, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Liberal Cage, Proofs with corrections (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Liberal Cage, Proofs with corrections (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Liberal Cage, TS poems (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Clifton, Harry, The Liberal Cage, TS with corrections (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Clifton, Harry, Night Train Through the Brenner, Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Clifton, Harry, Night Train Through the Brenner, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Clifton, Harry, Night Train Through the Brenner, Proofs (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Clifton, Harry, Night Train Through the Brenner, TS with corrections (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Clifton, Harry, Night Train Through the Brenner, TS with corrections (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Clifton, Harry, Office of the Salt Merchant, TS with corrections (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Coady, Michael, Biographical (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Coady, Michael, Correspondence, 1977-1987 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Coady, Michael, Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Coady, Michael, Correspondence, 1996-1998, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Coady, Michael, Miscellaneous (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Coady, Michael, Other published works (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Coady, Michael, TS poems (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Coady, Michael, All Souls, Book jacket material (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Coady, Michael, All Souls, Proofs with corrections (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Coady, Michael, All Souls, Proofs with corrections (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Coady, Michael, All Souls, Proofs with corrections (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Coady, Michael, All Souls, TS with corrections (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Coady, Michael, All Souls, TS with corrections (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Coady, Michael, "The Blind Arch," TS (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Coady, Michael, "Orate Fratres," Proof (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane original cover art by Michael Kane (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane, Proofs with corrections (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane, Proofs with corrections (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Coady, Michael, Oven Lane, TS with corrections (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Coady, Michael, Two for a Woman, One for a Man, TS with corrections (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Coady, Michael, The Well of Spring Water (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Cowman, Roz, Correspondence, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Cowman, Roz, Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Davison, Philip, Correspondence, 1991-1995 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Davison, Philip, "The Invisible Mending Company" (unpublished 1996 play), TS (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Biographical (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Book jacket material (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Correspondence, 1981-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Correspondence, 1993-1995 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Other published works (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Heart of Hearts, Artwork (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Heart of Hearts, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Heart of Hearts, Proofs with corrections (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Heart of Hearts, Proofs with corrections (photocopy) (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Heart of Hearts, TS with corrections (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Heart of Hearts, TS with corections (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, Proofs with corrections (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, Proofs with corrections (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, Proofs with corrections (Box 12, Folder 16)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, Proofs with corrections (photocopy) (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, TS with corrections (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Dawe, Gerald, The Lundys Letter, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Sheltering Places, TS (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Sunday School, Book jacket material (Box OP6)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Sunday School, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Sunday School, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Sunday School, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Dawe, Gerald, Sunday School, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Deane, Seamus [See: Hayes, Maurice (ed.), Flight Path] (Box -, Folder -)
    - Deane, Seamus, Book jacket material (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Deane, Seamus, Correspondence, 1979-1989 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Deane, Seamus, Miscellaneous (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Deane, Seamus, Other published works (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Deane, Seamus, History Lessons, Galley proofs with corrections (3) (Box OP7)
    - Deane, Seamus, History Lessons, MS poems (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Deane, Seamus, History Lessons, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Deane, Seamus, Selected Poems, Mock-ups with corrections (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Deane, Seamus, Selected Poems, Proofs with corrections (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Deane, Seamus, Selected Poems, Proofs with corrections (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Deane, Seamus, Selected Poems, TS poems (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Deane, Seamus, Selected Poems, TS with corrections (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Delanty, Greg, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Delanty, Greg, TS poems (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Delanty, Greg, "Answering the Sun" (unpublished collection), TS (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Delanty, Greg, "Summer Snowstorm" (unpublished collection), TS (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Donoghue, Denis, Correspondence, 1990 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Dunne, Seán, Biographical (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Dunne, Seán, Correspondence, 1984-1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Dunne, Seán, Correspondence, 1992-1996 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Dunne, Seán, Miscellaneous (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Dunne, Seán, Other published works (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Dunne, Seán, "Absence Notes," TS (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Dunne, Seán, "Requiem and Other Poems," Translation of Anna Akhmatova, TS with corrections (Box 14, Folder 12)